Vache Kodjavakian

312-285-5614 Vache72@hotmail.com

Professional Summary

Analytical problem solver with over 16 years of proficiency in Network and Office Operations and 9 years of experience in Management/ Project Manager. Areas of expertise include: Windows 7, 8, 10, Linux, Network Administration System Administrator, Windows Servers, Active Directory, Exchange, Microsoft Dynamics NAV, Storage, Hyper-V, VMware, Firewall, Switches. Cloud services, Office365, EDI, Operations Management, Policy, Procedure Development, Corporate Communications, Office Administration, Process Improvement, Telecommunications, Client Relations, ZenDesk, Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator /Acrobat, PDF Converter, Oracle, ESet ERP and Norton Antivirus Corporate Edition.

Skills

- Exchange Online, SharePoint Online, OneDrive for Business, and Skype for Business Online System
- Microsoft Exchange, Cloud services, Office365
- Router, firewall and VPN support/configuration
- Enterprise Backup, Antivirus, and Antispam
- LAN, WAN, WatchGuard firewall, SonicWALL firewall, Meraki firewall and VLAN
- Server hardware, Routing, LAN Environments, PC Desktop and Component

Work History

Kreg Therapeutics

Managing IT & Network Admin/Systems Admin

03/2018 to Present

- Managing Windows server 2008R2\2016 maintaining and updating active directory DHCP, DNS and VMware.
- Managing and supporting antivirus system Eset. Maintaining Windows Server updates as scheduled or needed.
- Managing and supporting 12 remote locations. Working and maintaining Desktops, Laptop, Tablets, Phones, and Jetpacks. Restoring and fresh installs of Operating System on the above devices. Used Meraki to manage most of the devices. Some tools and features might be proprietary.
- Managing Backup systems and file restores as needed.
- Maintaining and updating Visio diagrams for all locations.

Self-Employed/Consulting

Network Admin/Systems Admin

01/2017 to 02/2018

- Managing Windows server 2008R2\2012R2 maintaining and updating active directory DHCP, DNS and VMware.
- Managing and supporting antivirus varying from ESET, Norton corporate edition and Kaspersky. Maintaining Windows Server updates and weekly maintenance over a large organization.
- Working on desktops, Restoring and fresh installs of Operating System
- Managing Backup using VEEAM and Macrium.
- Maintaining and updating Visio diagrams for all locations.
- Developing and assisting on Proprietary add-on to existing platform.

SiPi Metals

Project Manager & Network Admin/Systems Admin

08/2014 - 05/2016

- Managed over 100 users in an Exchange environment with multiple domain controllers and five virtual machines running VMware VSphere 5.5. Within my first six months I facilitated the migration over to office 365 Cloud and worked towards building them to AD on the cloud and also Microsoft Azure.
- Administered Windows Server 2008R2 and Windows 2003 Server, Managing Active Directory, Microsoft Dynamics NAV, Wireless Access Point Router, Zebra Printer/Xerox Printers/Copier's, and Canon Printers/Copier's HP Laser Print, Managing Active Directory.

- Maintained the organization's local area networks, Email and wide area networks, Ticketing System. Analyzed products and recommended use of new products and services to senior management and all IT purchases. Perform LAN/WAN performance and security. Provided desktop software support, troubleshooting, website managing and basic updates.
- Managed the security system which included more than 5 DVRs.
- Managed all data and phone lines having three different data connections; 100 Meg fiber, 5 Meg Internet dish and bundle T3, Multiple PRI circuits and Pots lines.
- Managed the Shoretel System with over 125 phones 3 building. This included creating mailboxes, deleting mailboxes and extensions, programming custom buttons and login & logout options,

IMCP

IT Manager & Network Admin/Systems Admin

03/2009 - 08/2014

- Maintained 16 different locations and managed over 200 employee's accounts in Exchange and in Citrix. Also managed the camera, security systems and Allworx Voice over IP.
- Administered the Windows 2003 Server, Windows 2003 Small business Server, Windows Server 2008R2, Citrix Server, PRO 2040 Standard, Microsoft Dynamics NAV, Links Wireless Access Point Router, Ricoh Printers/Copier's, and HP Laser Print, Zebra Printer, Managing Active Directory.
- Maintained the organization's local area networks, email and wide area networks. Analyzed products and recommended use of new products and services to senior management and al IT purchases. Perform LANWAN performance and security. Provided desktop software support and troubleshoot user problems. Website Managing and Updates, Graphical, Video Editing.
- Overseen the data center for AT&T in Lisle IL, including its seven servers. Five of the servers were virtual and the
 other two were physical servers. Responsible for over 10 additional servers at the data center belonging to dental
 offices, construction companies, non-profit/governmental organizations and additional small businesses.
- Managed the process of posting job positions and also interviewing candidates.
- Managed and deployed the Security System DVR surveillance system which included more than 11 DVR at 11 different locations. Each of the DVRs had a static IP address which connected to a proprietary program that allowed multiple DVR to be view from one program.
- Created procedures and policies which were eventually integrated within the company's handbook and deploy to all staff
- Managed an Avaya IP 400 with over 100 phones in one building. This included creating mailboxes, deleting mailboxes and extensions.
- Managed an Avaya IP 500 with over 200 phones in one building. This included creating mailboxes, deleting mailboxes and extensions. (Avaya IP Office R7.0 Software) I managed and facilitated the deployment of this phone system.

Klein Tools Network Administrator

01/2002 - 11/2003

- Comprehensive background in the installation, upgrade, configuration, rollout and support of hardware, software, peripheral and network devices and infrastructure. Researched and purchased all new network equipment including switches, routers, servers, workstations and backup equipment. Desktop support for users including, MS Office, Windows 2000, Win Fax Server, Adobe Acrobat. Created and automated backup schedules using windows backup and Veritas Backup Exec. Deployed new policies and procedures which were integrated into the handbook for Human Resource. Initiated weekly meetings and training of the IT Team.
- Managed information technology systems and network operations, including server and router-based data solutions, document management systems and telephone. Worked with staff throughout the organization and including regional offices. Also assessed technology required to meet organizational goals and design computer-based solutions for these needs. Evaluated existing systems and recommended expansions, upgrades and changes. Researched technologies that can improve efficiency of corporate information systems. Recommended more efficient business processes. Planned and implemented all technical aspects of IT projects, including development of project requirements, budgeting for acquisitions and upgrades, purchasing of hardware and software.

Education

Oakton Community College. Skokie. IL 1992-1994 Niles West High School, Skokie, IL 1987-1991

Languages

English (Fluent) Armenian (Fluent) Korean (Some) Spanish (Some)